<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Sebastian Gräßl]]></title>
  <link href="http://bastilian.me/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bastilian.me/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-24T18:31:40+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://bastilian.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sebastian Gräßl]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fremdschämen]]></title>
    <link href="http://bastilian.me/blog/2013/03/24/fremdschamen/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-24T16:13:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://bastilian.me/blog/2013/03/24/fremdschamen</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://bastilian.me/images/posts/picard.jpg" alt="" /> In 2010 a new word in German has been crowned &#8220;Word of the Year 2010&#8221;. It means to feel ashamed on someone elses behalf and this is what I feel when I read or hear about how some male colleagues in my industry behave towards women. And i have the feeling these reports are getting more and more. Be it caused by more women in tech or by more women taking a stand. I welcome both and do my best I can to support them.</p>

<p>The mindset that these guys advocate, which is basically that women are not capable of being good in technology, is basically bullshit. There are plenty of colleagues out there who are female and without them we would not have decent <a href="www.molly.com/">Web Standards</a>, <a href="leahculver.com">OAuth</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ada_Lovelace">programming in general</a> and much more. I admire them, the same way I admire some men, for what they contribute(d) to the field.</p>

<p>To assume that men are better in technology, because there are more contributions out there from men is wrong. It is a fact that there are less women in our field, therefore more contributions are of male origin, which of course does not in any way mean they are more or less valuable.</p>

<p>I crave for equality in technology and basically in everything I am involved with, therefore: I want more women in tech!</p>

<p>I do my part by helping at <a href="http://railsgirls.com">Rails Girls</a> events and other workshops to get people started with programming and there are a bunch of guys, good guys, who give their support as well. If you are a woman who is interested in programming i highly encourage you to come to one of these events and see for your self that every male there is in no way to be associated with disrespecting douche-bags mentioned in this post at the top.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My albums of the year 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://bastilian.me/blog/2012/11/24/my-albums-of-the-year-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T19:06:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://bastilian.me/blog/2012/11/24/my-albums-of-the-year-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dicovering new music, listening to the latest album of my favorite artists, seeing them live. All that is a big part of my life, therefore i decided to show you my favorite albums of this past year. Of course there are much more albums I listened to, but these are the ones I still listen to.</p>

<h2>Mumford &amp; Sons - Babel</h2>

<p><img src="http://bastilian.me/images/posts/mands_babel.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p>What i loved about their previous album was there ability to build up tension within there songs and cause a amazing explosion of emotions. With this album the keep it this way. &#8220;I Will Wait&#8221; is the favorite of most on this record, it also is mine. I did not yet have the chance to see them live, but i imagine it an amazing concert.</p>

<h2>Band of Horses - Mirage Rock</h2>

<p><img src="http://bastilian.me/images/posts/BOH.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>I listened to &#8220;Knock Knock&#8221; when they revealed the video for it, before the album release. I was stunned. It was much more rocky then I expected. The whole album is more decorated with a lot more drums and and guitar action. Rumors say that even Jimmy Page likes it.</p>

<h2>Japandroids - Celebration Rock</h2>

<p><img src="http://bastilian.me/images/posts/06137_prc-238estore.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p>And a celebration of rock it is. &#8220;The House That Heaven Built&#8221;, what a song. When I hear it, I need to bang my head. It is impossible not to. After enjoying it for weeks I had to see them live. I went out of there completely soaked. Not onlye due to the fact that the little venue was packed.</p>

<h2>Best Coast - The Only Place</h2>

<p><img src="http://bastilian.me/images/posts/The-Only-Place-cover1.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>This album ruled my summer. Go out into the sun and turn on &#8220;The Only Place&#8221;. And dance. This is what it does to you. Here in vienna we don&#8217;t have the ocean, we don&#8217;t have the babes and we also don&#8217;t have the waves, but this makes you feel we do. It will probably continue to be a record I will listen to when I want to escape the city for a moment.</p>

<h2>Paul Banks - Banks</h2>

<p><img src="http://bastilian.me/images/posts/bankspackshot.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Oh, Paul. His solo project &#8220;Julian Plenti&#8221; was already a good move. Not saying Interpol isn&#8217;t good, but somehow his solo projects seem to bring out the best of him and suit his voice even better. Even though it is sometimes rocking it keeps you in a melancholic mood.</p>

<br style="clear:both"/>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
